「纏」　念オーラを 体の周囲に　とどめる技
Huh? That is the name the Queen gave me.
これにより　肉体は強靭となり 若さも保つ
From now on, call me Neferpitou.
ゴンの渾身の一発が ヒソカの顔面を捉えた
Amazing... He's been picking them up this entire time,
never losing them for an instant.
果たして　勝負の行方は…
Kite said he could use En within
a radius of forty-five meters.
クリティカル！ ２ポイント！　ゴン！ なんと！　ゴン選手に クリティカルヒットが出ました！
I've heard that those called Nen masters
can handle around fifty meters. Kite is nearly there.
これでポイントをひっくり返して ２対１。 ゴン選手　リードです！
Actually, given that he's kept
it up for an entire night, he's probably stronger.
ヒソカ選手　それほどダメージを 受けたようには見えません。
Then Kite's the real deal.
今の得点　やや疑問が残ります。
Yeah, he's the first real pro Hunter we've met.
審判にはポイントを つける際の好みがあるんだよ。 えっ？ ダメージ重視でポイントをつける 審判もいるし
Tsezgerra was a pro Hunter, but we really only knew him
as another player in a game.
戦術や技術を評価する審判もいる。
Bisky was an incredible Hunter.
今のは　石板を うまく攻撃に利用したところが
But to us... Yeah, she was our Nen mentor.
戦術点として 高く評価されたわけだな。
And the first to teach us about Nen...
なるほど。 で　あんた　誰？
Wing-san was our Nen master and savior.
よし！
Looking back, we always meet the right people
just when we need them most.
おっ？　おっと！
And those people have all made us stronger. Razor, too, huh?
ヒソカ選手 この試合　初めて動いた！
Yeah.
口元には 薄く笑みを浮かべております。
It's clear that Ging really did create
Greed Island to train you.
ここからが 本当の勝負ということなのか？
And once you beat the game,
he deliberately led you to Kite.
お！ 今のは一体　何だったんだ？ 分からん！
that you would like the man who
had earned Ging's respect. And he knew without doubt
that you would go with Kite.
「念」について
This is a pretty brutal place for training, though.
どこまで習った？ 基礎は全部。
That's why I keep asking if your resolve is firm.
えっ…　なっ　何で分かるの？ ウフフ…　君は　かわいいなぁ。 ダメだよ そんな簡単にバラしちゃ。
As you mentioned, Ging-san probably had certain
expectations when he sent you to me.
う…　うるさいなぁ 何で分かったんだよ!?
But I do not intend to train
you during this journey.
血液型性格判断と同じで 根拠は　ないけどね。
We don't have that kind of time.
僕が考えた　オーラ別性格分析さ。
I brought you along because I
thought you might be of use.
強化系は　単純一途！ えっ！ 合ってる… 合ってるっす…
From here, it all comes down to your resolve. If it's strong, you'll develop your Nen
and grow strong via combat.
ちなみに　僕は変化系 気まぐれで　ウソつき。
If it's weak, the Ants will eat you.
合ってる… 合ってる…
But we can't die...
放出系は短気　特質系は個人主義
We are pro Hunters.
具現化系は神経質 操作系は理屈屋。
Those who call themselves
Hunters always get their prey.
僕達は相性がいいよ 性格が正反対で引かれ合う。
For Hunters, that is the first commandment.
とっても仲良しになれるかも。
A hunt involves both hunter and prey.
だけど　注意しないと… 変化系は気まぐれだから
It is a battle of resolve.
大事なものが あっという間に　ゴミへと変わる。
Emerging victorious from a battle of resolve
is what makes a successful hunt. The loser has to follow the
winner's rules and customs.
だから…。
Rules...
僕を失望させるなよ　ゴン。
But to be a successful Hunter, you must
understand your enemy and yourself.
うっ！ 速い！
Th-That's why... That's why you hit me back then!
な…　何というキック力！
That's a territorial marker
made by Foxbears with cubs.
石板を登場ゲートまで 蹴り飛ばしました！
Any animal seeing it knows to get far away!
速い！　速い！　速い！
Do you remember what my final test was?
みせた　ヒソカ選手！　本気です！
Yeah, to find Ging.
クリティカル　ヒソカ！ プラスポイント　３対２！
Before the test began, Ging-san gave this to me.
目にも留まらぬ連続攻撃に クリティカルの採点！ あっという間に再逆転です！
He said I should use it to find him...
戸惑いのゴン選手 なすすべないのか！
I planned to return it to him once I did.
距離をとり直します。
Huh? He wouldn't take it back? No...
ヤダね！　作戦中！
Huh? Yeah.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
Then you have to do it. And would you return this for me?
あの速さ…
Sure!
目では何とか追えるけど 体がついて行かない！ このままじゃ やられっ放しだぞ！
But first, I have to finish this job
with you and get a lot stronger.
ふん　そうか。 それなら　無理にでも こっちに来てもらおうか。
After that, I'll find Ging and give this back. I promise!
ゴン！　「凝」だ！
Well, let's get a move on before we lose the trail.
何が起きるか　分かるかな？
Being average is terrible...
ぐっ！　うっ！
You have to go to all this trouble
just to unleash your power.
うわ！ あ！　ゴン選手が ヒソカ選手に引き寄せられる！
I want to find out how strong I really am.
これ　伸縮自在の愛 「バンジーガム」っていうんだ よく伸び　よく縮む
Found you...
つけるも剥がすも　僕の意思
Get away from me!
チッ つけるも剥がすもヒソカ次第
Idio—
うっ　クッソ！ ６対２　一気に 大差が　ついてしまいました！
Good decision, Killua.
やはり　ヒソカ選手の 無敵伝説は続くのか！
Take Gon and run!
立ったものの　ダメージは かなり大きいぞ　ゴン選手。
This time, you're in big trouble...
さて　ここで問題。 えっ？
Let's see if you get a good roll!
当たれば　タダで １発　殴らせてあげよう。 何！ 僕は　いつ　君のほっぺに 「バンジーガム」をつけたでしょう？
3! Ah, so you can do stuff like that?
３だ！　両手で殴った時だろ！ ブ！
We were overconfident...
にゅ！　汚っ！
The two of us were still weaker
than Kite who'd lost an arm.
クソ！　でも　ちゃんと始めから 「凝」を使っていれば…！
That thing knew. This is reality.
さて　１つ忠告しておこう。
If Kite had been alone, this probably wouldn't have happened.
君が「凝」を使っていれば 僕のオーラ別性格分析を 聞いている時でも
We were fools!
あ…。 気がついたかい？
Hey...
「バンジーガム」を つけることができる。 オーラを隠して使うのは 相手が油断している時だけ。
Look.
いや　防御もダメ。 ガードしても　その部分に つけられてしまう。
Huh? You left Kite behind?
あっ…　ん。
Why?! What happened?
逃げられない
Explain what's going on!
どうする!?
H-Hey, what are you doing?!
さぁ　お喋りは　ここまで。
Yes, I understand.
それじゃあ　そろそろ戦闘準備 再開。
Can you wait there a little longer? We're headed your way right now.
うっ…　うっ　あ！
What's this? They're just kids.
あぁ…　でも　ダメ　ダメ
If you're here to play, you'll get burned.
えい！ おぉ！　おっ！
Go back home.
もっと…　もっと…
Stop it, Morel-san.
崩すのが もったいなくなるぐらい…
That isn't nice...
ラッシュ！　ラッシュ！ ラッシュ！　ラッシュ！ 熟れてから ラッシュ！　ラッシュ！ ラッシュ！　ラッシュ！
They're only children.
我慢！ 猛ラッシュ！
You look pretty defeated.
あぁ…
Was the enemy that strong?
自ら　パンチを食らう！
One of them could use Nen.
うぐっ。
That was the worst aura I've ever encountered.
よし！　今のはガードしたぞ！
Worse than my brother's...
「バンジーガム」で いきなり引っ張られるのも
Worse than Hisoka's...
これから…　これからだ！
Now that I've learned Nen myself, I can tell.
怖い… でも　ここで恐怖に負けたら
You guys are unbelievably strong.
この先　どんな相手とだって 戦えっこないぞ！
But I still can't see you defeating that thing...
トータル　ヒソカ　９ポイント！ ゴン　４ポイント！ ダウンじゃないよ！ すぐ起きたもん！　ガードしたし！
Whenever humans encounter the unknown, they tend to lose perspective.
えっ！ 審判　おかしいぞ！ どこに目つけてんだよ　こら！
Currently, you're experiencing a state of panic.
さぁて　またしても疑惑の判定！ 採点基準への不満が ブーイングとなって
We'll take it from here, so go lie in bed.
会場を覆い尽くしております。 ファイト！
You're no better than I am, Knov.
１０ポイント取られたら負け… あと１ポイントしかない ダウンは　おろか
Kid... The minute you start talking about who
can win in a Nen fight, you're wrong.
まともに　攻撃を食らっても おしまいだ ウッフフフ…　油断大敵だよ　ゴン。
In most cases, you won't know
your opponent's abilities.
あっ。 右のほうを見てごらん。
One instant of carelessness
あぁ　ごめん 僕から見て　右のほうだった。
The battle can turn at any point.
がっ…。
That's what fighting with Nen means.
ダウン＆クリーンヒット！ あっ！ プラス２ポイント！　１１対４！
But regardless, you must always fight certain of victory.
ＴＫＯにより　勝者
That is a Nen user's spirit.
ヒソカ！
The moment you were overwhelmed
えっ？　あっ…。
by the opponent's aura and fled,
you were disqualified.
あぁ…。
You're lower than a loser! Morel, that's enough.
あ…。
Is Gon asleep?
君が審判に 文句を言っていた隙に
He was going to attack the enemy, so I used force to stop him.
左手のオーラを石に投げつけた。
I didn't have time to control my strength, so I don't know when he'll wake up.
((トータル　ヒソカ　９ポイント！ ゴン　４ポイント！))
That kid shows some promise, then.
すかさず「バンジーガム」で 素早く縮むように発動。 くっ…。
It's difficult to believe that giant
Chimera Ants are eating humans, but since it appears to be true, we must keep casualties to a minimum.
えっ　やっぱり　終わり…。 大した成長だ。
If we send fighters who aren't strong enough,
they'll only strengthen the enemy.
でも　まだまだ実戦不足。
Do you understand? Yeah.
いい勝負ができるように なるかもねぇ。
That's why there are only three.
あくまで　天空闘技場の中でだけ… ならだけど。
A select few...
だから　もう 君とは　ここで戦わない。
We're not strong enough.
次は　ルールなしの 真剣勝負の世界でやろう。 命を懸けて。
We sent two assassins to the nearest village.
遠い… けど 全然　届かないわけじゃ　ない
If you wish to live as a Hunter...
もっと　「念」を磨いて
We are not desperate for help.
ヒソカに負けない力を 見つける！
We only seek the strong.
審判によっては 危険な試合だと判断したら
The moment you were overwhelmed
ガンガン点数を与えて　早めに 決着つけることがあるんだ。
by the opponent's aura and fled,
you were disqualified.
ふん。
You're lower than a loser!
それも考えて　賭けないとな。 ああ！
I am no longer qualified...
絶対　１０対０でヒソカ だと思ったのになぁ。
Killua...
彼と戦ったゴンくん自身が 一番　分かっているでしょう。
Why would you thank me?
何が？
Weren't you the one who stopped me?
「何を得たか」です。 はい！ ゴン　何を得たんだよ。
Had I lost control back there,
I would've gotten in Kite's way.
内緒！ ちぇっ。 ゴンくん　キルアくん
Then, all three of us could have died.
ここからは　君達自身が それぞれの道を歩む中で
But I...
それぞれの「念」を 完成させてください。
I let Kite die... Kite is alive!
はい！ ああ。 自分　お２人に会えて よかったっす。
He wouldn't ever let that thing beat him!
超えるべき目標が出来て 努力のしがいがあるっす。 超えられると思ってんの？ いつか必ず。 無理　無理。
But considering his injury,
he'd have a hard time moving around.
楽しみに待ってるよ　ズシ。
So he's probably hiding.
オス！　エッヘヘ…。 じゃ　行こうぜ。 うん！
Waiting for us to return!
あっ　一応　俺も　サンキュー。
So we should hurry back...
２人とも　お元気で！
Once we're stronger.
ズシ！　いつか　また会おう！ オス！
To save Kite!
さて　これで　ようやく ゴンの目標クリアだな。 うん。
You are light.
くじら島に帰るよ。 くじら島？ うん。
Yeah, you're right.
とりあえず ヒソカに借りも返したし 島に帰って　ミトさんに ライセンスカードを見せたいんだ。
Sometimes, you shine so
brightly, I must look away.
もう　半年以上 帰ってないもんなぁ。
But even so, is it still okay
if I stay at your side?
俺も行こうかな。
Let's go.
えっ？ ミトさんに会ってみたいしさ。 本当？
To become stronger!
ヒソカに一撃を食らわし 約束通りプレートを返したゴン 戦いには敗れたものの
Prepare a freezer in the castle. We need one that can store
over a hundred humans.
目的を達成したゴンの気持は 爽やかだった
To ensure that our collection doesn't rot.